# FARAN NAVAZI

Austin, TX 78758

Phone: 512-577-9398 | Email: Faran.navazi@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <a href="https://github.com/FaranNavazi">www.linkedin.com/in/farannavazi</a> | GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/FaranNavazi">https://github.com/FaranNavazi</a> |

| Portfolio: https://farannavazi.github.io/

### **SUMMARY**

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in software development and life-long dedication to learning. Demonstrated work ethics and the ability to use knowledge and technical expertise to create user-friendly web applications. Known for strong leadership and project management skills with the ability to pay attention to details no matter the complexity of the project.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, React.js + React hooks, Node.js, Express.js, Handelbars.js, Firebase, API and Ajax call, MySQL, MongoDB, PHP, Heroku, postman, security and session storage.

## **PROJECTS**

Run Source | https://github.com/codemasterspro/CodeMasters

- Simple web App created to show user desire route on map with distance calculation and accurate, local full weather forecast.
- Core responsibilities for this project was the front-end and interactive looks of the web app.
- Tools used: HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, ¡Query, API's, Firebase, Google Analytics...

LIRI Bot | https://github.com/FaranNavazi/liri-node-app

- LIRI is a command line Node.js app that takes in parameters and returns you data from 3 different API.
- This was a one-man project and fully written by me.
- Tools used: JavaScript, Node.js, API's, NPM.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Data Analyst / Front-end Dev
Apex System at Apple Inc. (Signed NDA for description)

2019 – Present Austin, Texas

UI designer

2011 – 2012 Kaysari, Turka

Mehmet Aseman Computer

Kayseri, Turkey

Designing of user interface for machines and software such as computers with the focus on maxim

Designing of user interface for machines and software such as computers with the focus on maximizing usability and the user experience with Apps.

Key Accomplishments:

• 3 months back to back employee of the month for clean and readable codes.

## Security guard Travis County (Government)

2015 - 2019

Austin, Texas

Providing security for County facilities during normal business hours and after hours and on weekends and holidays. Reports security violations and questionable activities.

Key Accomplishments:

- Certification of completion and recognition for leadership and management skills.
- Design certain security protocols and SOP forms for County facilities.

# **EDUCATION**

**Certification:** University of Texas at Austin – Austin, TX

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

**Certification:** Pasargad Institute – Mashhad, Iran

Certification of completion in software development.